Guide to the Yale Student Papers Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Student essays in American Studies, 1950-1978; Accession 19ND-A-437
  - Crocker, Phyllis L. "The Status of Women in the American West Based on a Study of Their Daily Lives 1860-1880" Co-Winner 1978 Pearson Prize 57 pp. (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Croswell, Robert S. "Berwick: A post - WW II Camp Interpretation of the American Experience" 121 pp., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Crumpacker, Tom "A Comparative Study of the Development of French and American Syndicalism" 114 pp., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Crutcher, Lawrence M. "Horace Bushnell: Mediator and Apologist" 129 pp., 1964 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Curchack, Walter H. "Virginia Public Schools During Reconstruction" 182 pp., 1972 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Dalrymple, John S., III Oliver Dalrymple and His Bonanza" 189 pp., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Deitrick, Ira G., III "The Intergrated Vision of Robert Herrick" 91 pp., 1959 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Dentan, Robert K. "Through a Looking Glass Darkly: Movies and Ahab's Confrontation with Moby Dick" 90 pp., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - des Aulnois, Gilles Durant "Judge Frank and Legal Pragmatism" 143 pp., 1951 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Ditkoff, James H. "Racial Images in the Buffalo Public Schools" 112 pp., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Duemling, Robert W. "The Bay Area Style" 135 pp., 1950 (Box 8, Folder 45-46)
  - Dull, David A. "The Politics of Abolition: Moral Men and the Political Process, 1830-1860" 182 pp., 1971 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - (Copy 2 of above) (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Eisner, Richard "Earl Warren: The Individual and the State" 134 pp., 1956 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Eldridge, Douglas A. "The Humorous Response to Alienation in the Contemporary American Novel" 108 pp., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Elliott, Ted "The Peace We Won" 137 pp., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Epps, Augustus Charles, Jr. "Higher Education in Virginia: A Study of the State's Relationship With Its Colleges" 90 pp., 1970 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Feinstein, Steven F. "John Dos Passos: Participant-Critic" 137 pp., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Fiederowicz, Walter M. Connecticut 1800-1818: Competing Visions of the Good Society" 169 pp., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Fiffer, Steven J. "Transportation and the Mobility-Limited: A Tale of Two Cities" 92 pp., 1973 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Finberg, Alan R. "Three Americas - Ideological Warfare in the Scottsboro Cases" 217 pp., 1950 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Forand, Edward J., Jr. "Politics of the Unenfranchised: The 18-Year-Old Vote Campaign in Connecticut 1967-1969" 115 pp., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Foster, J.R. "Avant-Gardes in Painting and Photography Before the Armony Show: Henri and Stieglitz" 125 pp., 1971 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Foster, Mark W. "Law and the Modern Mind" 116 pp., 1965 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Fox, Robert T. "The American in Europe" 98 pp., 1953 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Frazzini, Stephen F. "Calvinism and Independence: John Witherspoon" 161 pp., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Freilich, M. Morton "Freedom in Crisis: The Japanese-American Evacuation" 167 pp., 1954 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Gardner, James Knoll "Donald Grant Mitchell 1822-1908 - IK Marvel" 176 pp., 1962 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Garnsey, Walter Wood, Jr. "The Progressive Dilemma in Municipal Government" 170 pp., 1967 (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Geisen, Arthur R., Jr. The Conversation of David Daggett and Connecticut" 100 pp., 1954 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Gilden, Jairus "W.E.B. Du Bois and the Socialist Movement" Co-Winner 1977 Pearson Prize 114 pp. (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Gillete, Howard R., Jr. "The Man With the Muckrake" 84 pp., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - Godfrey, Thomas R. "The Whaling Industry of New London, Connecticut" 126 pp., 1966 (Box 12, Folder 69)
  - Gold, Gerard G. "Legal Realism at Yale" 125 pp., 1963 (Box 12, Folder 71)
  - Goldstein, Warren "The Federal Reserve Act of 1913-A Legislative History" 172 pp., 1973 (Box 12, Folder 72)
  - Good, Stephen "Savagery, Civilization, and Evolution" 218 pp., 1971 (Box 12, Folder 73)
  - Green, Joseph B. "The Foundling of the Metrpolitan Musuem of Art 98 pp., 1969 (Box 13, Folder 74)
  - Handel, Thomas F. "The Airlines Strike of 1966: The Facts and the Issues" 97 pp., 1970 (Box 13, Folder 75)
  - Harvin, David T. "Party and Section in Congressional Voting During the Mexican War" 121 pp., 1967 (Box 13, Folder 76)
  - Haverfield, Robert A., "Politics in Wyoming Territory 1869-1875" 84 pp., 1966 (Box 13, Folder 77)
  - Heinberg, John D. "A Survey of American Thrift Attitudes and Practices" 135 pp., 1959 (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - Helzer, James A. "The Italo - Ethiopian Crisis of 1934-1935" 176 pp., 1968 (Box 13, Folder 79)
  - Hendel, Douglas Robert "School and Community" 142 pp., 1953 (Box 13, Folder 80)
  - Higgins, Stephen B. "Eye of the Storm" 91 pp., 1968 (Box 14, Folder 81)
  - Hilgenberg, John C. "Mencken of Baltimore" 99 pp., 1963 (Box 14, Folder 82)
  - Hilyard, David Mitchell "The Contemporary Negro Novel In America (1952-1963)" 132 pp. (Box 14, Folder 83)
  - Hoffman, Thomas "The Novels of John Barth" 128 pp., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 84)
  - Hoganson, Jerome L. "The Finns: Circumstances Attending Their Immigration to America" 178 pp., 1958 (Box 14, Folder 85)
  - Hooker, Arthur B. "Faith, Hope, and Violence" 192 pp., 1950 (Box 14, Folder 87)
  - Horowitz, Daniel "American Art at International Fairs in Europe: 1851-1900" 134 pp, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 88)
  - Horwitz, Stuart "A Study of the German-American Bund From Its Beginnings to 1941" 158 pp., 1959 (Box 15, Folder 89)
  - Hoyt, Richard M. "The Danbury Hatters Case" 101 pp., 1965 (Box 15, Folder 90)
  - Hutchinson, G. C., III "Advertising" 83 pp., 1957 (Box 15, Folder 91)
  - Hull, Roger Bradford "Yankee Dynasty: Career of Erastus Hodges 1781-1847" 83 pp., 1951 (Box 15, Folder 92)
  - Jacobi, Peter de Greeff "The Politics of Fusion: A Study of the New York City Municipal Election of 1937" 134 pp., 1969 (Box 15, Folder 93)
  - Johnson, W.J., Jr. "Sometimes the Magic Works" 133 pp., 1971 (Box 16, Folder 94)
  - Jones, Joel M. "The Economic Status of the Faculty Members of the American Institutions of the Higher Learning" 161 pp., 1960 (Box 16, Folder 95)
  - Kagan, David M. "Student Opinion: A Comparative Study of Five Samples" 272 pp., 1972 (Box 16, Folder 96-97)
  - Kaplan, Allan S. "Van Wyck Brooks: 1886-1925" 121 pp., 1957 (Box 16, Folder 98)
  - Kaplanoff, Mark D. "The Social and Economic Bases of New Hamsphire's Political Change, 1800-1805" 249 pp., 1969 (Box 17, Folder 99-100)
  - Katz, Richard "Dewey and Tillich on Human Nature and Morality" 181 pp., 1958 (Box 17, Folder 101)
  - Kavanaugh, Lowe Walters, Norman "The Cult of Jefferson- Rise of a Hero" 119 pp.(See Walters, Norman), 1950 (Box 17, Folder 102)
  - Klebanoff, Arthur "The Demographies of Politics; Legislative Constituencies and the Borough of Brooklyn" 105 pp., 1969 (Box 17, Folder 103)
  - Klugheit, Mark "The Acquisitive Ethic in American Literature" 112 pp., 1969 (Box 17, Folder 104)
  - Knoblanch, Loring W. "Politics in New Haven - 1765-1790" 85 pp., 1964 (Box 17, Folder 105)
  - Kompaniez, Peter K. "The Postures, Poetry, and Prose of Maxwell Bodenheim" 107 pp., 1966 (Box 18, Folder 106)
  - Kreiliry, Tilmon, Jr., " Out There, 1801-1824 and Landing Party, 1967-1969" 134 pp. (Box 18, Folder 108)
  - Krotter, Mark M. "The Theme of Transformation in the Works of Jack London" 163 pp., 1968 (Box 18, Folder 109)
  - Lenz, Theodore Warren "The Adams Brothers and Massachusetts History" 90 pp., 1966 (Box 18, Folder 112)
  - Levin, Norman Gordon, Jr. "A Thematic and Cultural Study of the Twentieth Century American War Novel" 134 pp., 1956 (Box 19, Folder 113)
  - Linett, David "American Secondary School Fraternities" 177 pp., 1956 (Box 19, Folder 114)
  - Lunt, Dudley C. "American Fascist Propaganda and United States Isolation" 97 pp., 1953 (Box 19, Folder 116)
  - McCarron, James P., Jr. "An Analysis of the Response of the American Literary Artist to the City at the Beginning of the Twentieth Century" 161 pp., 1964 (Box 19, Folder 117)
  - McConnell, E. Hoy, II "A New Era: The National Regulation of Advertising 1950-1960" 135 pp., 1963 (Box 19, Folder 118)
  - Marschner, Edward Charles "Dialogue to Ambivalence" 163 pp., 1966 (Box 20, Folder 119)
  - Mayer, W.S. "American Baseball" 84 pp., 1955 (Box 20, Folder 121)
  - Mayor, Richard B. "Currents in American Philanthropy" 170 pp., 1955 (Box 20, Folder 122)
  - Milius, Peter "The Thought of Richard Hildreth" 77 pp., 1958 (Box 20, Folder 123)
  - Mohr, James Crail "American Images of Napoleon" 85 pp., 1965 (Box 20, Folder 124)
  - Moore, Ralph Joseph, Jr. "The Background and the Symbol: Charles E. Ives" 184 pp., 1954 (Box 21, Folder 125)
  - Mostow, Carol Held "Interpreting the Experience of Change: American Immigration and a Family Case Study" Co-winner 1978 Pearson Prize 77 pp. (Box 21, Folder 127)
  - Nassau, Arthur M. "The Political Behavior of Hartford Jews" 102 pp., 1957 (Box 21, Folder 128)
  - Neely, Mark "The Mounted Regular in America, 1833-1848" 119 pp., 1966 (Box 21, Folder 129)
  - Newman, Charles H., Jr. "A Romantic in the Modern World: Hutchins Hapgood 1869-1944" 219 pp., 1960 (Box 22, Folder 132-133)
  - Okin, J. Thomas "The Sources of American Isolationism: 1935-1941" Porter Prize; 127 pp., 1956 (Box 22, Folder 134)
  - (Copy 2 of above) (Box 22, Folder 135)
  - Olasky, Marvin "Success and Failure in the Lives of Henry Adams and Samuel Clemens" 123 pp., 1971 (Box 22, Folder 136)
  - Ott, Gilbert R. "The New York Society for the Suppression of Vice" 93 pp., 1965 (Box 23, Folder 138)
  - Polikoff, Benet, Jr. "Heresy" 180 pp., 1959 (Box 23, Folder 140)
  - Prince, Gregory S., Jr. "Castles in the Air" 147 pp., 1961 (Box 23, Folder 141-142)
  - Putney, Freeman T., Jr. "Whispers and Al Smith" 128 pp., 1955 (Box 24, Folder 143)
  - Reisner, Robert A.F. "Efficiency in Philadelphia: Morris Cooke and the Application of Scientific Management to Government" 137 pp., 1968 (Box 24, Folder 145)
  - Reynolds, Bruce W. "The Establishment in Opposition: Congregational Social Values and the War of 1812" 154 pp., 1970 (Box 24, Folder 146)
  - Rice, Roger L. "Residential Segregation by Law: 1910-1917" 88 pp., 1965 (Box 24, Folder 147)
  - Richards, David A. "The Memorable Preservations" 112 pp., 1967 (Box 24, Folder 148)
  - Richman, Eli B. "The Dilemma of the Serious Negro Artist" 133 pp., 1959 (Box 25, Folder 149)
  - Riggins, Robert C.K. "Walt Whitman, Spokesman of the Democratic Faith" 115 pp., 1956 (Box 25, Folder 150)
  - Ritchie, A., II "James Rockwell Sheffield-A Biographical Essay" 187 pp., 1961 (Box 25, Folder 151)
  - Rogers, James G., III "James Gamble Rogers-Yale Architect" 138 pp., 1968 (Box 25, Folder 152)
  - (Copy 2 of above) (Box 25, Folder 153)
  - Rohner, J.T. "Herman Melville's Battle Pieces " 106 pp., 1962 (Box 25, Folder 154)
  - Ross, James R. "The Press, the Legal System, and the Seale Huggins Trial" 126 pp., 1972 (Box 26, Folder 156)
  - Schancupp, Robert N. "The Early Career of Philip Barry" 172 pp., 1956 (Box 26, Folder 157)
  - Schneider, Richard Graham "The Air Force Party Line and National Military Policy" 186 pp., 1952 (Box 26, Folder 158)
  - Schragger, Bruce M. "'Northeastern' - A Cooperative of Cooperatives" 139 pp., 1955 (Box 26, Folder 159)
  - Schwartz, Kenneth B. "The United States and the War Crimes Commission: Stalemate and Checkmate" Co-winner of 1977 Pearson Prize; 83 pp. (Box 26, Folder 160)
  - Seskin, Samuel Nelson "Essex and Chester, Connecticut, 1790-1850: A Study in Communal Identity and Social Continuity" 109 pp., 1972 (Box 27, Folder 161)
  - Sheldon, Charles "The Doubtful Journey-A Study of the Central Naugatuck Valley Regional Planning Agency" 140 pp., 1969 (Box 27, Folder 163)
  - Shober, John A.H. "John L. Lewis-Power Baron" 121 pp., 1955 (Box 27, Folder 164)
  - Shriber, H. Michael "Ability Groupings, 84 pp., 1959 (Box 27, Folder 165)
  - Shulman, Jerry L. "The Fair Packaging and Labeling Act" 122 pp., 1968 (Box 27, Folder 166)
  - Silver, Lawrence Roger "The Ante Bellum Political Career of Robert Toombs: Green Prize; 121 pp., 1959 (Box 28, Folder 168)
  - Simon, L. Linfield "Thurman Arnold in the 1930's" 116 pp., 1962 (Box 28, Folder 169)
  - Singer, George "Sargent and Company, 1864-1900: A Case Study in Economic Growth" 176 pp., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 170)
  - Singer, Richard C. "Lomex: The Story of the Lower Manhattan Expressway" 190 pp., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 171)
  - Smith, Whit "The Regualtion of Connecticut's Electric Utilities: 1912-1929" 119 pp., 1968 (Box 28, Folder 172)
  - Starbird, L.R. "The Liberals and Liberalism: A Study in Rationalism" 107 pp., 1954 (Box 28, Folder 173)
  - Steele, Peter "Students for a Democratic Society, 1960-1967-The Formative Years" 98 pp., 1970 (Box 29, Folder 174)
  - Stein, John Hollister "Congress Enacts the Landrum-Griffin Law" 188 pp., 1964 (Box 29, Folder 175)
  - Sternberg, David "Arthur Miller-His Tradition and His Work" 111 pp., 1958 (Box 29, Folder 177)
  - Stewart, T.L. "Veblen's Vision of History" 172 pp., 1971 (Box 29, Folder 178-179)
  - Stokely, James R. "A Crisis in Leadership: The Douglas Dam Controversy of 1941-1942" 100 pp., 1972 (Box 30, Folder 180)
  - Stuchin, Miles M. "New Rochelle: Battleground of Schools, Homes, and Churches" 137 pp., 1973 (Box 30, Folder 181)
  - Stuhr, Walter M., Jr. "The Church and Church Architecture-Mid-Twenieth Century" 132 pp., 1954 (Box 30, Folder 182)
  - Sullivan, Robert E. "The Connecticut Dairy Farmer" 77 pp, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 183)
  - Sutherland, Hugh C. "The Shattered World of James Fenimore Cooper" 146 pp., 1964 (Box 30, Folder 184)
  - Thompson, David M. "The Continuing Rediscovery of Thoreau in the Twentieth Century" 110 pp., 1968 (Box 30, Folder 185)
  - Tolles, Robert E. "Christian Science" 121 pp., 1950 (Box 31, Folder 186)
  - Toma, John "Origins of the Tennessee Valley Authority" 80 pp., 1965 (Box 31, Folder 187)
  - Train, John K., III "Walter White: A Study of a Man and His Time" 196 pp., 1960 (Box 31, Folder 188)
  - Travis, Jeremy W. "Frederick Douglass and Martin Robinson Delany; 126 pp., 1970 (Box 31, Folder 189)
  - Tully, Paul "Initiation of a Federal Draft" 99 pp., 1968 (Box 31, Folder 190)
  - Turner, Jere D. "John P. Marquand: The Novelist's Role in a Scientific View of Society" 146 pp., 1953 (Box 31, Folder 191)
  - Viener, John D. "A Sense of Obligation-Henry L. Stimson as United States Attorney, 1906-1909" 137 pp., 1961 (Box 32, Folder 193)
  - Vojta, George John "Schmucker and Lutherans" 98 pp., 1957 (Box 32, Folder 194)
  - Wagman, Paul "Rebels and Dropouts in Contemporary American Fiction" 104 pp., 1970 (Box 32, Folder 195)
  - Wainwright, Jonathan M. "Everett Shinn" 105 pp., 1965 (Box 32, Folder 196)
  - Walters, Norman Kavanaugh, Lowe "The Cult of Jefferson-Rise of a Hero" 119 pp., 1950 (Box 32, Folder 197)
  - Warner, James "The Streamline; Industrial Design in America, 1927-1939" 70 pp., 1975 (Box 33, Folder 198)
  - Waxman, Jonathan H. "The Marshall Court and Congress" 151 pp., 1964 (Box 33, Folder 199)
  - Werthan, Morris "The Objectives and Strategy of the N.A.A.C.P., 1909-1957" 154 pp., 1959 (Box 33, Folder 201)
  - Wild, Henry S. "Kennedy and the Press-the First Two Years" 127 pp., 1963 (Box 33, Folder 202)
  - Wilmer, Stephen E. "Divided We Fall" 162 pp., 1968 (Box 34, Folder 205)
  - Wolfe, Andrew M. "Caroline Gordon and the Fiction of Southern Agrarianism" 124 pp., 1966 (Box 34, Folder 206)
  - Wright, James R., Jr. "The Oklahoma Constitutional Convention: A Case Study of Southern Progressivism" 174 pp., 1969 (Box 34, Folder 207)
  - Yanowitz, Herbert W. "Wiretapping: Its Ingenuities, Its Impact, and Its Implications" Patterson Prize; 174 pp., 1958 (Box 34, Folder 208)
  - Yingling, John E., Jr. "Television: A Technological History" 159 pp., 1955 (Box 34, Folder 209)
  - Zaleznik, Dori "Image Politics and the Mass Media: Francis Sargent's Gubernatorial Campaign, 1970" 119 pp., 1971 (Box 34, Folder 210)
- Student engineering papers, 1941; Accession 1990-A-026
  Scope and Contents
  Transferred from the Map Collection, SML
  - Resurvey of Boundary on Watrous Farm East Lyme, Conn. Party R.M.S. Walker, W.L. Nimick, J. Rabinowitz, J. Porto. "1 inch - 1.21 Ch." 52 x 34 cm. Ms. map., 1941 September 8 (Box AF9)
  - Stadia Map of Rogers Farm Yale Engineering Camp East Lyme, Conn. Drawn By: W.L. Booth. 1:600. 72 X 53 cm. Ms. map., 1941 September (Box AF9)
  - Exercises in Map Drawing prepared by S. Thorne Jr. covering parts of neighborhood of Yale Engineering Camp. various scales. 4 sheets, various sizes. Ms. maps., 1941 (Box AF9)
- McBrayer, Martha, oral interviews of Ku Klux Klan members, 1984; Accession 1998-A-027
  - McBrayer, Martha (1984), oral interviews of Ku Klux Klan members (Box 1)
- Report on the "Engineering Inspection Trip" by Edward B. Nitchie (1931S), Accession 2001-A-130
  - Nitchie, Edward B. (1931S), report on the "Engineering Inspection Trip," (Box 1)
- Essays and papers on philosophy, 1939-1942; Accession 2003-A-054
  - Papers and notes by Millner, Bernard N., 1939 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Intrinsic Value and Christmas donations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Millner, B.N., Phil 37, Northrup, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Physical Theory of Nature, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Knowledge and Causation in the Philosophy of David Hume, senior thesis for the Philosophy department. (part 1 and 2), 1942 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Hume's Philosophy of Human Nature by Bernard N. Millner, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2003; Accession 2004-A-046
  Conditions Governing Access
  Requires written permission of the author or copyright holder to copy.
  - Badlani, Chirag, "Walking the Line of Diplomacy: The Mutual Failures of Chester Bowles and the United States in India, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Winner of the 2003 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay prize for MSSA research
    Copy of paper is not available
  - Burke, Chris, "I'll Be Seeing You: Yale University in World War II", 2003; 1 (Box 2)
  - Heaney, Christopher H., "Hiram Bingham and the "Lost Treasures" of Machu Picchu: Popular Archaeology, Imagined Imperialism, and National Press in the Yale Peruvian Expeditions", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hoffman, Jean, "Textbooks in Context: An Analysis of the Yale Law School and Its System of Instruction From 1891-1903", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Klay, Benjamin, "The End of ROTC at Yale", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lindsay, Molly Emma, "The Yale Mission and the Power of the Nation: Land Acquisition by Foreigners in Late Imperial China, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mechoulam, Patricia, "Dulce Et Decorum Est Pro Patria Mori: Commemorating Yale's Experience of the Great War", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Waldman, Elizabeth, "What's in a Name: History of the School of Forestry and Environmental Studies", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Winner of the 2003 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay prize on Yale
  - Zaremby, Justin, "A Progressive Leap Backwards: A History of the Directed Studies Program", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2004; Accession 2004-A-187
  - Finkelstein, Laura, "Disclosure of Holocaust Experience,", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Winner of the 2004 Senior Essay prize for MSSA research
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2005; Accession 2005-A-182
  - Chwialkowska, Sandra, "It's About College"
    Winner of the 2005 senior essay prize on Yale.
    - Master, 1 (Box 2)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 2U)
  - Coyle, D. Tyler, "Athletics, Scholarship, and the Clean Living Movement at Yale University From 1890-1920: A Balancing Act", 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Glogower, Ari, "American Studies and the Idea of America at Yale: 1946-1969", 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Huang, Melvin, "Holy Fire and Living Water: The Yale College Revival of 1831", 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lalka, Robert Tice, "Surviving the Death of God: Existentialism, God and Man at Post-World War II Yale", 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Winner of the 2005 senior essay prize for MSSA research.
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2006; Accession 2006-A-203
  - Blair, Edith Baily, ""That Colonization Should Flourish in Such a Soil is but to be Expected": Reevaluating the Triumph of Abolitionism through the Analysis of the White Community in New Haven, 1830-1840", 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dosik, Diana, "For Sera, For Science, and For Yale: Serological Sleuthing and the Kissing Disease", 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gegenheimer, Julia K., "Between Rhetoric and Reality: The Effect of Ideological Transition in 1970s-1980s on the Status of Women in the Sudan", 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Winner of the 2006 Senior Essay prize on Yale
  - Leuver, Mary Ellen, "Defying Death, Disease, and Darkness: Yale, New Haven, and the Institutionalization of Public Health in America 1880-1930", 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Winner of the 2006 Senior Essay prize for MSSA research
  - Syverud, Steven, "The Changing Processes and Values of Merit: A Study of One Year in the History of the Yale Admissions Office", 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Essays submitted for Manuscripts and Archives senior essay contest, 2007; Accession 2008-A-044
  - Adler, Daniel, "Hanson W. Baldwin and Further Limitations on a Critical U.S. Press During the Vietnam War", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beaty, Andrew, "Student Radicalism and the 1975 Woodward Report: Freedom of Expression at Yale", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bressler, Jonathan, "The Red Badge of Infamy: John Punnett Peters and the Fate of the Federal Employment Loyalty Program", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Winner of the 2007 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay prize for MSSA research
  - Busick, Matthew, "Becoming a Yale Man: Intimacy Among Yale Students in the Nineteenth Century", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Winner of the 2007 Manuscripts and Archives senior essay prize on Yale
  - Coppola, Lauren, "The Conversion of Dwight Macdonald: From Meta-politician to Culture Critic", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Feinstein, Eric, "The Development of United States Cultural Diplomacy: Chester Bowles in India, 1951-1953", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Frick, Ali, "The Mingled Dust of Both Armies: Yale's Compromised Civil War Memorial", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Goldman, Jennifer E., "Y Women: Why Kingman Brewster Reluctantly Co-Educated Yale College in 1969 and how the First Yale Women Fared", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lewis, Dain, "The Developer's Game: The Private Sector and the Church Street Project, 1955-1964", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Porter, Karen, "American and the Armenians 1915-1921: Principle, Power and the Making of U.S. 'Humanitarian' Foreign Policy", 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- History of Art senior essays, 1987-2000; Accession 2009-A-042
  - Roberts, Ellen: J.M. Whistler's The Riva, Sunset: Red and Gold, 1995 (Box 1)
  - White, Tara: A Reach for theobjective, A Ressurectionof the Image, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Sando, Holly: The Red, White, Black and Blue, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Diana Dreyer: Postmodernism and Sots Aesthetic, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Breslow, Rebecca: Wenceslaus Hollar's Costume Series, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Rohan, Timothy: Salvator Rosa's Influenceon Arists and Writers in Romantic England, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Working Papers: AIDS and its Representations, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Clancy, Brian: Carlo Rainaldi A Fourth in the Great Triadof Italian Baroque Master Architects, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Kleinbub, Christian: The Significanceof Garden-like Spaces, and Garden Iconography in Veronese's Paintings, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Breuer, Marcel: Modernity in the Eyesof a Humanist, 1998 (Box 1)
  - ogilvie, Sarah: The (Mis)Representationof Women in Senufo Sculpture, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Brittenham, Claudia: Tikal's Central Acropolis, 1998 (Box 1)